A new powerful presentation of the most loved ghost story of all time!
A Christmas Carol is a drama, fantasy, tv movie film directed by Clive Donner.
Miser Ebenezer Scrooge is awakened on Christmas Eve by spirits who reveal to him his own miserable existence, what opportunities
he wasted in his youth, his current cruelties, and the dire fate that awaits him if he does not change his ways.
Scrooge is faced with his own story of growing bitterness and meanness, and
must decide what his own future will hold: death or redemption.
Ebenezer Scrooge, played by George C. Scott.
Fred Holywell / Narrator, played by Roger Rees.
Bob Cratchit, played by David Warner.
Mrs. Cratchit, played by Susannah York.
Ghost of Christmas Present, played by Edward Woodward.
Ghost of Christmas Past, played by Angela Pleasence.
A Christmas Carol is a 1984 Christmas fantasy television film adapted
from Charles Dickens' novella A Christmas Carol (1843).
The film was directed by Clive Donner, who was an editor of
the 1951 film Scrooge, and stars George C.
Scott as Ebenezer Scrooge.
It also features Frank Finlay as Marley's Ghost, David
Warner as Bob Cratchit, Susannah York as Mrs.
Cratchit, Angela Pleasence as the Ghost of Christmas Past, Edward Woodward as the Ghost of Christmas Present and Roger Rees as
Scrooge's nephew Fred; Rees also narrates portions of Charles Dickens' words at the beginning and end of the film.
It was filmed in the historic medieval county town of Shrewsbury in Shropshire.
The film has received significantly positive reviews, with general praise going to the sets, soundtrack, cinematography, and the performances of the
cast, particularly Scott's portrayal of Scrooge, with many critics and reviewers considering it one of the best adaptions of the novel.
The film explores themes of future, based on novel or
book, holiday, redemption, charity.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.